oxygenmag.com 2013-05-03

# Oxygen Women's Fitness Magazine | Privacy Policy

**Privacy Policy**

Your privacy is important to us. Robert Kennedy Publishing, it’s subsidiaries and affiliates (collectively, “RKP”, “us”, “our”, “we”) are committed to maintaining the privacy, security and accuracy of the personal information they collect, use and disclose in accordance with public legislation. We strive to offer the visitors of our websites including [www.eatcleandiet.com](http://www.eatcleandiet.com/), [www.cleaneatingmag.com](http://www.cleaneatingmag.com/), [www.emusclemag.com](http://www.emusclemag.com/), [www.oxygenmag.com](http://www.oxygenmag.com/), [www.americancurvesmag.com](http://www.americancurvesmag.com/), [www.maxfitmag.com](http://www.maxfitmag.com/), [www.repsmag.com](http://www.repsmag.com/) (collectively, the “Site”) the many advantages of Internet technology and to provide an interactive and personalized experience. This privacy policy (the “Privacy Policy” is a statement of principles and guidelines concerning the protection of personal information of our individual clients, individual service providers and other individuals (“you”) (with the exception of personnel, whose personal information is collected, used and disclosed in accordance with our Personnel Privacy Policy). By using our Site or any of our products, offerings, features, tools or resources that we provide on our Site, including our products or offerings for personal digital assistants or other handheld mobile devices, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY, PLEASE DO NOT CONTINUE USING THIS SITE. CONSENT BY SUBMITTING PERSONAL INFORMATION RKP OR ITS AGENTS, YOU AGREE THAT WE MAY COLLECT, USE AND DISCLOSE SUCH PERSONAL INFORMATION IN ACCORDANCE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND AS PERMITTED OR REQUIRED BY LAW. Subject to legal and contractual requirements, you may refuse or withdraw your consent to certain of the identified purposes at anytime by contacting us. If you refuse or withdraw your consent, we may not be able to provide you or continue to provide you with certain services or information that may be of value to you. 

**WHAT PERSONAL INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?**

How we collect and store information depends on the page you are visiting, the activities in which you elect to participate and the services provided. For instance, you may chose to become a member of the Site (“Member”) in order to participate in certain activities on the Site and enjoy special benefits offered only to Members. To become a Member, you are required to sign in by providing your name, postal address, and email address. The types of identifiable personal information that we may collect from you from time to time include: your name, address, telephone number, e-mail address, your forwarding address (e.g. during a vacation), previous address(es), payment information (for billing purposes), and delivery instructions. In addition, from time to time, we may ask you to provide us with more detailed information regarding your interests, occupation and background. For example, we sometimes ask our customers to complete surveys in order to get a better sense of who they are and what issues, products or services may be of interest to them and our readership. Finally, from time to time, we may acquire demographic and other information about you (e.g. your occupation and interests). 

**WHY DO WE COLLECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We collect your personal information for the purposes listed below:

**a) To provide the product, service or information you requested** If you are a customer of one of our publications, we use your name and address (postal and/or e-mail) in order to deliver the product, service or information you requested and to follow up with you about the transaction (i.e., sent a bill, notify you that your subscription is expiring, etc.). If you enter into a contest offered through one of our websites or printed publications, we use your personal information to administer the contest on our own behalf or on behalf of our sponsors.

**b) To process payment** Your credit card number, debit card number, or banking information for pre-authorized payments is used only for processing payments and for presenting you with payment options – not for marketing purposes.

**c) To send you information** From time to time we may send you further information about the publication, its offers, or other products produced under its name. 

**d) Other purposes** In addition, from time to time, we may use your personal information for the following purposes: 

  * to detect and protect RKP and other third parties against error, fraud, theft and other illegal activity, and to audit compliance with RKP policies and contractual obligations;

  * to understand your needs and preferences, including to contact and communicate with you and to conduct surveys, research and evaluations. It is optional for you to submit some demographic information, but providing this information is encouraged so we can provide a more personalized experience on our Site;

  * to obtain audit statements regarding numbers of subscribers per publication;

  * to engage in business transactions, including the purchase, sale, lease merger, amalgamation or other type of acquisition, disposal, securitization or financing involving RKP;

  * for any other purpose we may indicate to you from time to time.

You do not have to provide us with your personal information to visit our website. However, if you choose to withhold requested information, you may not be able to visit all sections of our Site or use all of our online products. 

**TO WHOM DO WE DISCLOSE YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We may disclose your personal information to the following third parties in the following circumstances:

**a) Disclosure to Service Providers** We may disclose your personal information to other companies that provide services on our behalf, including label printers, invoice printers, fulfillment contractors, auditors, our software developers (including website developers and hosts), data processing, document management and office services. In addition, we may disclose your personal information to an organization or individual retained by RKP to evaluate your creditworthiness or to collect debts outstanding to an account or to our auditors. We will only provide those companies the information they need to deliver the services and they are prohibited from using that information for any other purpose.

**b) Disclosure to Affiliates and Business Units** We may disclose your personal information to any of the companies and business units that form part of the RKP group in order to serve you better and to provide you with information about our group’s products and services.

**c) Disclosure to Trading Partners** From time to time our magazines or websites may make their list of customers available to other carefully screened organizations that want to let you know about a product or service that might interest you. The material sent to you is reviewed by us before the names and addresses (including e-mail address) are released to ensure the organizations is reputable and material is appropriate and not misleading.

**d) Disclosure in Business Transfers** RKP may be involved in the sale or transfer of some or all of its business. As part of that sale or transfer, RKP may disclose your personal information to the acquiring organization, but will require the acquiring organization to agree to protect the privacy of your personal information in a matter that is consistent with this Privacy Policy.

**e) Law Enforcement and Legal Disclosure** RKP may disclose your personal information to a government institution that has asserted it’s lawful authority to obtain the information or where RKP has reasonable grounds to believe the information could be useful in the investigation of unlawful activity, or to comply with a subpoena or warrant or any order made by a court, person or body with jurisdiction to compel the production of information, or to comply with court rules regarding the production of records and information, or to RKP’s legal counsel. 

**CONTROL OF YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION**

At RKP, we want you to be able to maintain control over how we use your personal information. In particular: 

  * You always have the option to instruct us to not use your name, address, e-mail address, etc. beyond providing you with the product, service or information you requested. See “Contact Us” below. 

  * E-mail communications will always include an identification of the sender and an “unsubscribe” option.

As mentioned before, we may not be able to provide you with our services if you withdraw your consent to our use of your personal information. 

**WHERE IS YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION STORED?**

Your personal information is stored in secured locations and on servers controlled by RKP, located either at our offices or at the offices of our service providers. 

**HOW DO WE PROTECT YOUR PERSONAL INFORMATION?**

We make every reasonable effort to protect against loss, misuse, and alteration of personal information under our control. Our security policies are periodically reviewed and enhanced as necessary. Only authorized employees and suppliers have access to your personal information. Where information is sent to a third party for processing, we make sure, through our contracts with them, that all your information is kept secure. We keep your information for the time we are providing you with a product or service, and for a reasonable time thereafter in the event that you wish to resume service. We do not collect personal information from bulletin boards or forums. However, we cannot guarantee that personal information voluntarily disclosed in chat rooms or discussing boards will not be collected and used by others, which may result in unsolicited messages to you from other parties. 

**PRIVACY AND OUR WEBSITES**

RKP sometimes collects personal information through its various websites. In this section, we provide you with additional information regarding such collection.

**Online Communications** – In order to provide our website visitors with a product, service or information, visitors may voluntarily submit personal information to us for purposes such as asking a question, obtaining information, subscribing to, reviewing or downloading a publication, participating in contests and surveys. If you are known to RKP as a registered user of an online service, we may combine and store personal information about your use of our websites and the online information you have provided with certain other online and offline information we may have collected. 

**E-mail Communications** – Occasionally, we may send marketing or promotional e-mail communications to you with information that may be useful, including information about the products and services of RKP and other third parties with whom we have a relationship. We will include instructions on how to unsubscribe and inform us of preferences if recipients decide they do not want to receive any future marketing or promotional e-mails from RKP. Also, if you send us an e-mail message, we may retain that message and your e-mail address, as well as any response we send to you. 

**Technical Data –** When you visit our Site, we may collect various types of technical data. This data includes (but is not limited to) domain and/or web browser information. We may track which website you visited before arriving at the Site and the Web site you link to when you leave the Site. We may keep a record of which pages of the Site you visit, and how long you spend on each page. 

**Cookies** – Cookies are small pieces of information that our server places on a visitor’s computer hard drive to enable that person to more easily communicate and interact with the Site and to provide us with important information on how visitors use the Site. Further, cookies and other technologies are used in e-mail messages sent by our e-mail delivery and marketing company and at our website to help us measure the effectiveness of our advertising and how visitors use our site. With respect to ads, information about your visits to this site, such as number of times you have viewed an ad (but not your name, address, or other information), is used to serve ads to you. Many web browsers are automatically set to accept cookies. You may change your browser settings to either reject cookies or notify you when a cookies about to be placed on your computer. Please note, however, that rejecting cookies while visiting the Site may result in certain parts of the Site not operating correctly or as efficiently as if they were allowed. Cookies must be enabled in order to register with the site.

**Advertisers** – If you submit some of your personal information on any RKP website to request information from a third party (such as an advertiser), we are not responsibly for any use of your personal information by such third party. Hence, we suggest you first learn more about such third party’s privacy policies prior to submitting your personal information by visiting its website or contacting it by postal mail or telephone. 

**Network Advertising** \- We allow third-party companies to serve ads and/or collect certain anonymous information when you visit our web site. These companies may use non-personally identifiable information (e.g, click stream information, browser type, time and date, subject of advertisements clicked or scrolled over) during you visits to this and other Web sites in order to provide advertisements about goods and services likely to be of greater interest to you. These companies typically use a cookie or third party web beacon to collect this information. To learn more abut this behavioral advertising practice or to opt-out of this type of advertising, you can visit [networkadvertising.org](http://networkadvertising.org/).

**Opinion Polls –** Opinion polls on our websites are anonymous. We do not correlate votes submitted via such polls with names or individual e-mail addresses, unless otherwise disclosed at the point of collection. 

**Chat Rooms and Bulletin Boards** – Some of RKP’s websites offer chat rooms and bulletin boards (forums). Only individuals 18 years of age or older may participate in our chat rooms and bulletin boards. The voluntary disclosure of personal information in a chat room or on a bulletin board is not governed by this Privacy Policy. Any communications which are part of chat rooms or bulletin boards are public and not private and you provide such information at your own risk. Although it is prohibited to use our forums as a source of e-mail addresses for sending unfounded or unsolicited messages or spamming, others may still capture your e-mail address and send you e-mail messages if you post your e-mail address and we cannot control such actions by others. We advise you to remain prudent and attentive at all times when you are on line on the internet. 

**Searches** – For your convenience, search functions are sometimes provided on our websites. We keep logs of the words searched to learn more about what kind of information our visitors are seeking, and thus improve our services. 

**Hyperlinks** – For your convenience, RKP’s websites sometimes contain hyperlinks to websites managed by third parties. By activating these hyperlinks, you will leave RKP’s websites for those of the third parties, which may have different privacy policies and practices than RKP. RKP cannot be held liable for use of such third party websites. 

**Individuals Under 18 –** No personal information should be submitted or posted on our websites by individuals under 18 years of age without their parent’s or guardian’s permission. We may request name, address, phone number, e-mail address and date of birth from an individuals under 18 years of age for contest participation so that we may notify him or her if selected as winner. In the event we do so, we will request their parent’s or guardian’s consent prior to collection. 

**Sharing of User Content on the Site** When users send stories, recipes, photos and/or other User Content, these materials may be posted on our Site. We will not use materials without the acceptance by the user of our Terms of Use Agreement. We will not return any materials, such as photographs, once they have been sent to us.

No information collected from online guests under 18 years of age is used for any marketing or promotional purposes whatsoever by RKP. Unless otherwise disclosed at collection, we do not provide any personal information collected through any RKP website from individuals under 18 years old, regardless of its source, to any third party for any purpose whatsoever. 

**CONTESTS, SWEEPSTAKES, RAFFLES, GAMES AND SIMILAR PROMOTIONS**

We may operate contests, sweepstakes, raffles, games and similar promotions through the site. We typically ask for personal information when you enter and, if applicable, win a sweepstakes, contest, raffle, game or similar promotion. We reserve the right to share this personal information with third party sponsors of such sweepstakes, contests, raffles, games and promotions (irrespective of whether it is hosted by us), or otherwise in accordance with the rules applicable to such sweepstakes, contests, raffles, games or promotions. You should carefully review the rules of each contest, sweepstakes, raffles, games or promotions in which you participate through the Site, as they may contain additional important information about RKP’s or a sponsor’s use of your personal information. To the extent that the terms and conditions of such rules concerning the treatment of your personal information conflict with this policy, the terms and conditions of such rules shall take precedent over this Privacy Policy. 

**CHANGES TO PRIVACY POLICY**

RKP reserves the right to modify or supplement this Privacy Policy at any time. However, RKP will obtain the necessary consents required under applicable Privacy Laws if it seeks to collect, use or disclose an individual’s personal information for the purposes other than those to which consent is obtained unless otherwise required or permitted by law. THIS POLICY WAS LAST UPDATED APRIL 1st/2009 AND IS EFFECTIVE IMMEDIATELY. 

**BY USING OUR WEBSITE, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE WITH THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE OUR WEBSITE. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF OUR WEBSITE FOLLOWING THE POSTING OF CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY WILL MEAN THAT ACCEPT THOSE CHANGES.**

Thank you 

**CONTACT US**

If you have any questions regarding our Privacy Policy, contact RKP here: RKP Privacy Policy 400 Matheson Blvd W. Mississauga, Ontario L5R 3M1 905-507-3545 E-mail: [privacy@rkpubs.com](mailto:privacy@rkpubs.com?subject=Questions%20about%20the%20Oxygenmag.com%20privacy%20policy)
